TASHIK MOIN

A computer scientist with experience in software development, cloud computing, and deep learning who enjoys working in devsecops culture and automation environments having microservice architecture. Capable of learning advanced tools and technologies, and loves to solve complex real-world problems.

+92-300-0212027 tashikmoinsheikh@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Automation Engineer - Part-time, ETS Square, Melbourne, Australia

June 2021 - PRESENT

Worked with the automation and orchestration tools (Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, etc) and managed containerized applications with CI/CD pipelines.

Cloud Infrastructure Engineer - Part-time, PlugCloud INC, San Mateo, USA

September 2019 - 2021

Worked with the Infrastructure as Code (IaC) technology, orchestration, and configuration tools to easily manage large complex cloud infrastructures.

Lab and Teaching Assistant - NUCES FAST, Karachi, Pakistan

January 2020 - PRESENT

Responsible for grading and assisting students in the courses' data structures(CS218), object-oriented programming (CL217), and theory of automata(CS301).

PROJECTS

CodeClassy, Final year project

A collaboration system for teachers and students having features (classroom, manual and auto-assessment and evaluation, individual student progress analysis, group assessments, real-time coding environment, remote code execution, etc) and stack (NestJS, NextJS, TypeScript, MySql, DevOps, and automation tools, etc).

Terrabuzz

A social media web application built with hybrid databases (MySql, MongoDB) and MERN stack, Nginx web server, Docker containers, and Microsoft Azure.

Audio Classification

Implemented an Artificial Neural Network using PyTorch for classifying the audio signals using Mel-frequency cepstrum coefficients (MFCC).

CFG Parser

Defined a set of recursive rules for validating context-free grammar patterns.

Unix Shell

A shell interpreter built with C++ and Python to execute Linux commands, download YouTube videos, and send text messages on WhatsApp using CLI.

Secure Messenger

A secure messenger application using Python with the FTP server hosted at Microsoft Azure. A private tunnel between two azure regions was also implemented via peering for secure communication.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science from National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences – FAST, Karachi. August 2018 - May 2022 CGPA: 3.43

CERTIFICATION

Cloud Computing (Microsoft – AZ-900, AZ-303, and AZ-500 | Oracle – 1Z0-1084, 1Z0-1067, 1Z0-1085, and 1Z0-931)

Development (Microsoft – C# 70-483, Python 98-381, MVC 70-486, and 98-961)

SKILLS

Networking, OS, version controlling, containerization, configuration, and orchestration (Nginx, HAProxy, Traefik, Linux, Git, GitHub, Docker, Ansible, Kubernetes, Terraform, and Jenkins)

Cloud computing (Microsoft Azure, and AWS)

Programming and Databases (Shell, C, C++, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle DB, and MongoDB)

Frameworks & Libraries (.NET Core 5, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NextJS, Redux, OpenMP, MPI, NumPy, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, and Pandas)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT for years 2020, and 2021)

Microsoft Gold Ambassador and Student Partner (July 2019 - PRESENT)

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

BSCS Deans' list of honors (Spring 2019, 2020, and Fall 2020, 2021)